export const series = [
  { question: " 1, 2, 5, 7, 11,______,17", options: ["12", "13", "14", "15"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " 1, 8, 27,____,125", options: ["37", "47", "54", "64"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 6, 12, 21, 33,____", options: ["38", "40", "45", "48"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 2, 20,____,110, 182", options: ["56", "72", "90", "96"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " 81, 9, 64,____,49, 7", options: ["8", "9", "10", "11"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " 15, 20, 30,_____,65", options: ["35", "40", "45", "50"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 18, 30, 48, 72, 96,______", options: ["106", "115", "120", "96"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 12, 32, 72, 152,_______,632", options: ["515", "613", "815", "312"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 1, 2, 3, 5, 7,______,13", options: ["8", "9", "10", "11"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 3, 8, 22, 63, 185,_____", options: ["285", "295", "310", "500"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 4, 5, 7,_____, 19", options: ["56", "66", "11", "17"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 27, 24, 30, 27, 33,______", options: ["48", "27", "30", "24"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 4, 10, 22, 46,_______", options: ["56", "66", "76", "94"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 4, 1, -8,_______,-20, 29, -32, 43", options: ["15", "16", "17", "18"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " 2, -2, 7, 3, 17,_______,32, 13", options: ["70", "10", "9", "8"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 9, 15, 23, 33,_______", options: ["44", "36", "38", "45"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 12, 8, 14, 6,________,4", options: ["5", "21", "24", "16"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 16, 12, 64, 16,_____,20, 256", options: ["18", "144", "20", "196"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " 2, 6,_____,120, 720, 5040", options: ["12", "18", "24", "60"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 9, 6, 16, 10, 30, 18,____,34", options: ["36", "60", "58", "60"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 10, 18, 34,_______,130, 258", options: ["32", "60", "68", "66"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 30, 23, 17, 12,________,5", options: ["6", "7", "8", "9"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 285, 253, 221, 189,_______", options: ["173", "167", "157", "146"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 8, 10, 14, 18,_______,34, 50, 66", options: ["28", "27", "26", "25"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 29, 36, 44, 53,_______", options: ["55", "63", "65", "69"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " 10, 22, 27,_______,44, 56, 61", options: ["32", "39", "40", "42"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " 2, 10, 60, 420, 3360,_________", options: ["30240", "27840", "25140", "222240"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " 5, 8, 12, 17, 23,_______,38", options: ["26", "28", "30", "29"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " 4, 9, 20, 43, 90,______", options: ["180", "182", "179", "185"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " 5, 9, 16, 29, 54, 103,________", options: ["102", "294", "203", "200"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
];
export const alphabetSeries = [
  { question: " J,L,N,P,R,T,________", options: ["V", "X", "Y", "Z"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " C,F,I,L,O,R,_________", options: ["V", "U", "W", "X"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " B,F,J,N,R,V,_________", options: ["X", "Y", "Z", "C"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " E,J,O,T,Y,D,_________", options: ["J", "K", "I", "F"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " AD, EH, IL, ____, QT, UX", options: ["MP", "MN", "MO", "MQ"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " B, I, P, W, D, K,_________", options: ["Q", "R", "S", "T"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " AZ, BY, CX, D________", options: ["E", "W", "R", "V"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " A, C, F, J, O,____________", options: ["U", "C", "D", "F"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " C, J, P, U, Y,____________", options: ["C", "D", "B", "A"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " AZ, BY, CX, DW, ______", options: ["EX", "EU", "EY", "EV"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " aa HI cc, cc JK ee, ee LM gg, ____", options: ["ff NO ii", "gg NO ii", "gg ON ee", "ee ON ii"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " aBEf, bCFg, cDGh, _______", options: ["dEGi", "dHIg", "dEHi", "dHEi"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " A, C, B, E, C, G, D,___ ____", options: ["M,N", "L,M", "I,E", "G,H"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " CD, GH, KL, OP, ST, ________", options: ["RS", "QR", "GH", "WX"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " WZI, EHJ, XAK, _____, YBM, GJN", options: ["ZCO", "IFL", "FFL", "FIL"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " BHL, DJN, FLP, ___________", options: ["HNR", "HOS", "IOS", "INR"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " B,E,I,N,T,___________", options: ["R", "U", "S", "A"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " BC, FG, JK, _________, RS, VW", options: ["LM", "OP", "QR", "NO"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " XD, WC, _________, YA", options: ["XY", "CD", "ZB", "WV"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " AI, BJ, CK, _________", options: ["LM", "DL", "GH", "SE"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " AM, BN, EI, FJ, CO, DP, GK, ________", options: ["HL", "PQ", "QR", "HG"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " Z,W,S,P,L,I,E,___________", options: ["F", "G", "B", "K"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " BD, EH, IM, NS, ______", options: ["UY", "UZ", "TY", "TZ"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " AC, EG, BD, FH, IK, _________", options: ["JL", "OP", "IJ", "JK"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " m NN o PP q _________", options: ["rr", "RR", "ss", "QQ"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " CGKOS, AEIMQ, EIMQ___,", options: ["W", "X", "V", "U"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
  { question: " AGMS, agms, _______________", options: ["ABCD abcd", "abcd ABCD", "BHNT bhnt", "bhnt BHNT"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "series" },
  { question: " aa, bbb, cccc, ______________", options: ["ddd", "ddddd", "dddd", "DDDD"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "series" },
  { question: " ACF acf G_______", options: ["IL gil", "JL gil", "IL gjl", "LL gli"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "series" },
  { question: " aB bB cD dD _________", options: ["ef", "gH", "fG", "eF"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "series" },
];

export const analogy = [
  { question: " SCISSORS : CLOTH ::", options: ["Axe : Wood", "Stone : Grinder", "Knife : Stone", "Gun : Hunt"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " FOOD : HUNGER ::", options: ["Axe : Wood", "Stone : Grinder", "Knife : Stone", "Gun : Hunt"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " BIRD : NEST ::", options: ["dog : doghouse", "squirrel : tree", "beaver : dam", "cat : litter box", "book : library"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " DALMATIAN : DOG ::", options: ["Nightingale : bird", "horse : pony", "shark : great white", "ant : insect", "stock : savings"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " DOCTOR : HOSPITAL ::", options: ["sports fan : stadium", "cow : farm", "professor : college", "criminal : jail", "food : grocery store"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " CUB : BEAR ::", options: ["piano : orchestra", "puppy : dog", "cat : kitten", "eagle : predator", "fork : utensil"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " NOODLES : FLOUR ::", options: ["snacks : breakfast", "Tomato : gravy", "beans : coffee", "thread : cotton"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " INK : PAPER ::", options: ["Pen : pencil", "Paint : painting", "Chalk : blackboard", "Carbon paper : ballpoint"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " ROCK GARDEN : CHANDIGARH ::", options: ["Delhi : Red Fort", "Film Studio : Pune", "Chicago : USA", "India : Asia"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " LIGHT : CANDLE ::", options: ["Exercise : Strength", "Heat : Coil", "Power : Battery", "Automobile : Engine"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " VOLCANO : LAVA ::", options: ["Death : Sorrow", "Rock : Sand", "Delta : River", "Fault : Earthquake"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " SCALES : FISH ::", options: ["Lady : Dress", "Skin : Man", "Tree : Leaves", "Bird : Feather"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " PETAL : FLOWER ::", options: ["salt : pepper", "tire : bicycle", "base : ball", "sandals : shoes", "puppy : dog"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " BRISTLE : BRUSH", options: ["arm : leg", "stage : curtain", "recline : chair", "key : piano", "art : sculpture"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " WOOL : WARMTH", options: ["spring : elasticity", "marketing : advertising", "person : success", "radio : broadcast"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " ODOMETER : DISTANCE", options: ["scale : weight", "length : width", "inch : foot", "mileage : speed", "area : size"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " WRITER : PEN", options: ["pencil : eraser", "ball pen : notebook", "typewriter : paper", "blacksmith : hammer", "gun : hunter"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " PEDAL : BICYCLE", options: ["inch : yardstick", "walk : skip", "tire : automobile", "buckle : belt", "oar : boat"], correctAnswer: 4, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " RIBS : LUNGS", options: ["ball : sphere", "hand : finger", "shell : nut", "coat : tie"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " BIRD : CAGE", options: ["animal : zoo", "thief : prison", "antique : museum", "crime : punishment"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " WAR : DESTRUCTION", options: ["fire : burn", "court : justice", "water : drown", "food : hunger"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " YEN : CURRENCY", options: ["brass : metal", "flower : fragrance", "paper : book", "karnataka : state"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " BINDING : BOOK", options: ["criminal : gang", "display : museum", "artist : carpenter", "nail : hammer", "frame : picture"], correctAnswer: 4, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " EXPLORE : DISCOVER", options: ["read : skim", "research : learn", "write : print", "think : relate", "sleep : wake"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " COTTON : BALE", options: ["butter : churn", "wine : ferment", "paper : ream", "curd : cheese", "beef : steak"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " STOOL : BENCH", options: ["chair : table", "carpenter : chair", "foot rule : yardstick", "glass : cup"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " LAWN : GRASS", options: ["wool : sheep", "skin : goat", "fur : animal skin", "rice : farm"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " WAITRESS : RESTAURANT", options: ["doctor : diagnosis", "actor : role", "driver : truck", "teacher : school", "author : book"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " FINCH : BIRD", options: ["frog : toad", "elephant : reptile", "Dalmatian : dog", "collie : marsupial", "ant : ladybug"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " RAIN : DRIZZLE", options: ["swim : dive", "hop : shuffle", "juggle : bounce", "walk : run", "run : jog"], correctAnswer: 4, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " EGG : OMELETTE", options: ["dam : river", "student : classroom", "clay : pottery", "onion : salad"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "analogy" },
  { question: " TAILOR : SUIT", options: ["scheme : agent", "edit : manuscript", "revise : writer", "mention : opinion", "architect : building"], correctAnswer: 4, type: "analogy" }
];
export const codingDecoding = [
  { question: " In a certain coding system MOTHER is coded as PQWJHT, how will you code SISTER?", options: ["VKUVHT", "VKVVHU", "VKVVHT", "VKVVHS"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " In a certain coding system PRICE is coded as SVNIL, how will you code COST?", options: ["FSXY", "FSWY", "FTWZ", "FSXZ"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " In a certain coding system FLOWER is written as SEXOMF, how will you code GARDEN?", options: ["OEERBH", "OFESBH", "OEESBG", "OEERBG"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " In a certain coding system TRAIN is written as GIZRM, how will you code FIGURE?", options: ["USTGKV", "VTYXTC", "URTFIV", "VKGTSV"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If SINGLE can be given a code number of 66, what code number can be given to WINKLE?", options: ["76", "66", "78", "74"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If REASON is called as 5 and BELIEVED as 7, what is the code number for GOVERNMENT?", options: ["10", "8", "9", "6"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If PRATAP could be given a code number 1618120116, what code number can be given to NAVIN?", options: ["73957614", "24639125", "14122914", "19274651"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If CENTURION is coded as 325791465, and RANK as 18510, what will the figure 78510 represent?", options: ["TANK", "BANK", "TAKE", "SANK"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If WORK is coded as 4567 and MAN 328, then WOMAN is coded as", options: ["45328", "43528", "32845", "35428"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If spider is written as PSDIRE, how would COMMON be written in that code?", options: ["OCOMMO", "OCMMNO", "OCMOMN", "OCMMON"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If 'gnr tag zog qmp' stands for 'Seoul Olympic organizing Committee', 'hyto gnr emf' stands for 'Summer Olympic Games', and 'esm sdr hyto' stands for 'Modern Games History', what would 'summer' stand for?", options: ["gnr", "hyto", "emf", "zog"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " In a certain language ‘526’ means ‘sky is blue’, ‘24’ means ‘blue colour’ and ‘436’ means ‘colour in fun’. Which digit in that language means ‘fun’?", options: ["2", "3", "4", "6"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If a rectangle is called a circle, a circle a point, a point a triangle, a triangle a square, then a wheel is a:", options: ["rectangle", "circle", "point", "triangle"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If the letters in PRABA are coded as 27595 and THILAK as 368451, how can BHARATHI be coded?", options: ["96575368", "57686535", "96855368", "37536689"], correctAnswer: 0, type: "coding-decoding" },
  { question: " If JAILAPPAS is coded as AIJAPLASP, ECONOMICS will be coded as:", options: ["COEMONCSI", "COEOMNCSI", "OECMONSCI", "OECOMNCIS"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "coding-decoding" }
];
export const arithmaticReasoning = [
  { question: " Rajesh walks 7 km to the north then turns left and walks 3 km. Then takes another left and continue walking this time another 7 km forward. How much distance in km is he away from the starting point?", options: ["10km", "6km", "3km", "2km"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " Balwant had 17 sheep. A storm in the village killed all but 7 sheep. How many was he left with?", options: ["10", "6", "7", "9"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " What is the smallest number of ducks that can swim in this formation- two ducks in front of a duck two ducks behind a duck and a duck between two ducks?", options: ["3", "5", "7", "9"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "logical" },
  { question: " What is the product of all the numbers in the dial of a telephone?", options: ["1,58,480", "1,59,450", "1,59,480", "None of those"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " A group of 1200 persons consisting of captains and soldiers is travelling in a train. For every 15 soldiers there is one captain. The number of captains in the group is", options: ["85", "80", "75", "70"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " Aruna cut a cake into two halves and cuts one half into smaller pieces of equal size. Each of the small pieces is twenty grams in weight. If she has seven pieces of the cake in all with her, how heavy was the original cake?", options: ["120 grams", "140 grams", "240 grams", "280 grams"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " First bunch of bananas has ¼ again as many bananas as a second bunch. If the second bunch has 3 bananas less than the first bunch, then the number of bananas in the first bunch is", options: ["9", "10", "12", "15"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " At the end of a business conference the ten people present all shake hands with each other once. How many handshakes will there be altogether?", options: ["20", "45", "55", "90"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "combinatorics" },
  { question: " A student got twice as many sums wrong as he got right. If he attempted 48 sums in all, how many did he solve correctly?", options: ["12", "16", "18", "24"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " There were 28 people at last week’s board meeting. If the ratio of men to women was 4:3, how many women were at the meeting?", options: ["16", "12", "7", "4"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " At a certain corporation, the ratio of clerical workers to executives is 7 to 2. If a combined total of 81 clerical workers and executive workers for that corporation, how many clerical workers are there?", options: ["9", "14", "18", "63"], correctAnswer: 4, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " Last Year, there were 720 crimes committed in the ninth precinct. These crimes involved theft, rape, and drugs in the ration of 4:2:3, How many crimes involved drugs?", options: ["80", "160", "240", "320"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " A unit price is a ratio that compares the price of an item to its unit of measurement. To determine which product is the better buy, calculate each one’s unit price. Which of these five boxes of Klean-O Detergent is the best buy?", options: ["Travel-size: Rs. 100 for 5 Kg.", "Small: Rs. 200 for 11 KG.", "Regular: Rs. 400 for 22 Kg.", "Large: Rs. 700 for 40 Kg."], correctAnswer: 4, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " Rimmy pulse rate is 19 beats every 15 seconds. What is her rate in beats per minute?", options: ["76", "60", "57", "45"], correctAnswer: 1, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " If you write down all the numbers from 1 to 100, then how many times do you write 3?", options: ["11", "18", "20", "21"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " The total number of digits used in numbering the pages of a book having 366 pages is", options: ["732", "990", "1098", "1305"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " In a garden, there are 10 rows and 12 columns of mango trees. The distance between two trees is 2 meters and a distance of one meter is left from all sides of the boundary of the garden. The length of the garden is", options: ["20 m", "22 m", "24 m", "26 m"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " A farmer built a fence around his square plot. He used 27 fence poles on each side of the square. How many poles did he need altogether?", options: ["100", "104", "108", "None of these"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " An enterprising businessman earns an income of Re.1 on the first day of his business. On every subsequent day, he earns an income which is just double of that made on the previous day. One the 10th day of business, his income is", options: ["Rs. 29", "Rs. 210", "Rs. 10", "Rs. 102"], correctAnswer: 2, type: "arithmetic" },
  { question: " In a family, the father took ¼ of the cake and he had 3 times as much as each of the other members had. The total number of family members are", options: ["3", "7", "10", "12"], correctAnswer: 3, type: "arithmetic" }
];

